A Guide to the Junior Order United American Mechanics Blue Ridge Council no. 149, 1902-1980
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Junior Order United American Mechanics Blue Ridge Council no. 149, 1902-1980
The Library of Virginia
32038
3.2 cu. ft. and 7 boxes
Junior Order United American Mechanics Blue Ridge Council no. 149
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Gift of Gerald K. Monger, Trustee, Blue Ridge Council no. 149, Junior Order United American Mechanics, 205 Virginia Avenue, Elkton, Virginia.
Historical Information
Blue Ridge Council no. 149, Junior Order United American Mechanics was founded in Rockingham County, Virginia, by 1902. Swift Run Council no. 26, was founded by 1908, but disbanded in 1914. Island Ford Council no. 204 was founded by 1912.
Scope and Content
Records, 1902-1980, of Blue Ridge Council no. 149, Junior Order United American Mechanics consisting of minute books containing minutes, lists of officers, dues paid, reports, receipts, correspondence, applications, dismissals, petitions, proclamations, warrants, and other papers regarding the operations of the council; membership and roll book listing officers, members, former councilors, honorary members, deceased and sick members, rejected applications, expelled and suspended members; membership book containing list of members and copy of by-laws; proposition books recommending potential members; pledge books for new members to pledge to support the organization and its objectives and containing name, age, birth place, health, and faith; and posters for field day activities, 1941-1947. Records also include minute book and treasurer's report book for Swift Run Council, with minute book containing correspondence concerning its disbanding; a pledge book for Island Ford Council no. 204; and membership books for Swift Run and Island Ford containing lists of officers, members, past councilors, honorary members, rejected applications, suspended members, record of sick benefits paid out, and abstracts of reports.
Contents List
- Blue Ridge Council no. 149, 1902-1980., Extent: 7 boxes. (Box 1-7)
  - Minute book, 7 January 1902-29 January 1906 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minute book, 1 January 1906-14 June 1909 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Minute book, 5 July 1909-1 July 1912 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Minute book, 1 July 1912-[13] September 1915 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Minute book, 20 September 1915-14 October 1918 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minute book, 11 November 1918-1 November 1920 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minute book, 8 November 1920-[28] July 1924 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minute book, 11 August 1924-29 August 1927 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minute book, 5 September 1927-4 November 1930 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minute book, 10 November 1930-15 January 1934 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minute book, 22 January 1934-1 March 1937 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minute book, 8 March 1937-5 February 1940 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Minute book, 12 February 1940-28 December 1942 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Minute book, 1 November 1948-24 November 1951 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Minute book, 13 June 1960-13 May 1963 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Minute book, 11 April 1966-29 June 1970 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Minute book, 29 June 1970-3 September 1973 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Minute book, 10 September 1973-1 November 1976 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Minute book, 7 November 1976-9 June 1980 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Membership and roll book, 1902-1923 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Membership book including by-laws, 1902-1914 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Proposition book, 1902-1911 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Pledge book, 1902-1912 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Pledge book, 1911-1934 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Pledge book, 1934-1949 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Field Day posters, 1941, 1942, 1947, no date (Folder oversize)
- Swift Run Council no. 26, 1908-1914., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  - Minute book, 1 October 1910-5 September 1914 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Membership and roll book, 1908-1914 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Treasurer's book, 1908-1914 (Box 7, Folder 5)
- Island Ford Council no. 204, 1912-1921., Extent: 1 box. (Box 1)
  - Membership and roll book, 1912-1921 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Proposition book, 1912-1921 (Box 7, Folder 7)